## Jake Weber

## Consumer Lifecycle Specialist & Data Druid

A curious spirit, effervescent soul, and meticulous mind drive Jake at his core. With 4.5+ years of experience in Consumer Lifecycle Management and Data Analytics, he's gotten to wear many hats. Learning Acquisition through Digital & Growth Marketing, he optimized a monthly budget of \$2 million by creating a FICO-based attribution model paired with vendor reallocation recommendations. In supporting the Vans Loyalty Program, he collaborated on **Engagement** strategies which grew the Member base from 4 million to 16+ million in 3 years (Compound Annual Growth Rate exceeding 50% year-over-year). In the realm of **Retention**, Jake customized an RFM model with in-app event data to identify high-value consumers with a propensity to churn. Outside of work, you'll most likely find him caring for his collection of exotic houseplants or practicing the piano.





mr.jake.weber@gmail.com



760-533-3756



Irvine, CA (Open to Relocation)



www.jakeweber.io

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior Consumer Growth Analyst** MFour Mobile Intelligence

12/2021 - 03/2022

Market Research & Technology

#### Driving Quantitative & Qualitative Consumer Insights

- Introduced and analyzed the effects of Sweepstakes as a major driver for engagement allowing us to reduce the volatility of our Weekly Active Users (WAU) and create better benchmarks for forecasting.
- Developed dashboards that deliver the Week-over-Week program health at a high level with Campaign Performance and Member Demographics.
- Conducted Cohort analyses to develop an understanding of engagement allowing us to create segmented personas and reduce acquisition spend.

## **Consumer Data Quality Analyst** Vans

11/2019 - 12/2021 Fashion & Action Sports

Enabling Creative Self-Expression and Living "Off the Wall"

- Introduced an RFM analysis to deepen the understanding of the consumer base while cultivating new personas for marketing segmentation.
- Performed analytical deep-dives to share insights surrounding marketing campaigns, product collaborations, and brand engagement.
- Identified inefficiencies within the weekly reporting process and developed an Alteryx alternative which reduced total processing time by 62.5%.
- Identified inactive consumers for a database hygiene initiative that reduced operational costs by \$60k+ per year.

## TECH SKILLS

SQL for Data Wrangling

R for Data Analysis

Alteryx for Data Workflows

Tableau for Data Visualization



## SOFT SKILLS

Curious

Creative

Collaborative

Attention to Detail

Ouick Study

## **EDUCATION**

## Marketing & Business Analytics Chapman University

09/2014 - 05/2018

Notable Achievements

- Captain of the **Chapman University** Men's Swim Team
- NCAA DIII All-Academic Team & Chapman University's Provost List

GPA: 3.5

- Vice-President of Logistics for Chapman Beta Theta Pi
- Head of Philanthropy for Chapman Beta Theta Pi

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Consumer Lifecycle Management Analyst Vans

04/2019 - 11/2020 Fashion & Action Sports

Enabling Creative Self-Expression and Living "Off the Wall"

- Utilized Alteryx and Tableau to measure the impact of 15 million members across various parts of the business, such as their total contribution to revenue and underlying purchasing behaviors across product categories.
- Conducted A/B testing related to the Loyalty Program, CRM, and in-store strategy, such as driving lower-funnel performance and evaluation of segment engagement.

#### **Data Scientist**

## AutoGravity

05/2018 - 11/2018 Finance & Technology

Automating the Acquisition of Automobiles

- Designed complex queries to facilitate ad hoc analysis and contribute to an early data warehouse project.
- Enabled stakeholders to make data-driven decisions by learning their objectives, arming them with existing data, creating new features for exploration, and developing Tableau dashboards for automated reporting.
- Identified ideal merchant partnership opportunities by comparing market research with internal data leading to the first monetized deals.

## **Digital Marketing & Data Science Intern** AutoGravity

09/2017 - 11/2018
Finance & Technology

Automating the Acquisition of Automobiles

- Spearheaded a competitive SEM analysis of keywords and ads to create a bidding strategy for under-valued keywords which lowered acquisition costs by shifting spend to a more efficient mix.
- Developed reporting for media performance with deeper insight into individual campaigns and customer segmentation.

## **FIELDS OF EXPERTISE**

#### Consumer Lifecycle Management

Acquisition, Engagement, & Retention; Customer Segmentation & Persona Development; A/B Testing & Experiment Design; Paid Media & Campaign Performance; Consumer Demographic, Transactional, & Behavioral Insights

#### **Data Science**

Data Wrangling, Transformation, & Visualization; Data Engineering; Big Data & Cloud Technologies; Relational Databases; Statistical Analysis; Storytelling & Information Design; KPI Development & Feature Engineering; Reporting & Dashboarding; Automation & Personalization.

#### **Technical Tools**

SQL, R, Tableau, Alteryx, AWS, Snowflake, Salesforce, Google Analytics, Adjust, Mixpanel, Amplitude

### LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

# Marketing & Data Science Internship Lead AutoGravity

05/2017 - 11/2017

Automating the Acquisition of Automobiles

- Developed an internship program with Human Resources for students during the Summer of 2017.
- Taught the fundamentals of data analysis with Excel, SQL, and Tableau with various exercises, shadowing, and in-depth projects.
- Took on the first mentorship opportunity available through the program which resulted in a unique Brand Activation initiative.

## **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

Horticulture	Yoga	Piano	
Dungeons & Dragons		Philosopl	hy

#### **PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES**

#### Lalida Kwok: Senior CLM Analyst at Vans

"Jake is an incredible colleague. He is unique in his ability to weave his interests and knowledge together and has great talent in data and analytics. He is simultaneously technically adept and business savvy all while taking the time to create meaningful relationships with those he works with. During the last few years I worked with Jake, whether it be our discussion on strategizing new ways to uniquely pull segments or getting his thoughts on a deck, he was able to pull experience and ideas from multiple areas to give great input and feedback. He is a fantastic and talented human being."

Contact: 626-488-6550

#### Mark Humphrey: Vice-President of Business Development at AutoGravity

"Jake Weber is an enthusiastic and hard-working young man, who I believe would be an asset to any team he joins. He is highly innovative and detail orientated with a strong will to learn, consistently asking questions to extend his own knowledge and understanding. He impressed me with his ability to quickly comprehend new, complex ideas and works well under challenging conditions. Jake is a problem-solver who sees a challenge as an opportunity to grow, displaying character and desire that are must have characteristics I look for during the hiring process. Jake has a great future ahead of him for any of his career aspirations."

Contact: 714-330-2405

## Danny Salinas: Director of Data Science at AutoGravity

"Jake is everything you look for in an analyst. He is not simply curious about how things work but is always looking for better ways to get the job done. He is hard working and dedicated to doing something right the first time. He is an amazingly fast learner who picks up new skills like a sponge. He is extremely coachable and looks forward to all feedback. But probably my favorite thing about him is he is an absolute pleasure to work with and the kind of person who makes your day brighter from just interacting with him. Jake is a superstar, and I look forward to hearing more about his accomplishments in the near future."

Contact: 310-956-0553

